# **Arafat Zahan**

### Full-stack Web & Mobile Application Developer

**Address:** 30/53 Shahibag, Savar, Dhaka - 1340 **Cell:** +880 1841 832 034 | +880 1957 832 034

Email: arafatzahan2018@gmail.com Web: https://kuasha420.github.io



### Career Objective

I am a full stack web developer and an aspiring mobile application developer with more than seven years of experience in the industry. I have experience in developing highly specialized websites & mobile applications using modern technologies like WordPress and React Native. I'm also well versed in DevOps and System Administration. Problem solving is my speciality. My aspiration is to gain employment in a dynamic environment where I can sharpen my existing skills, acquire new talents and use all my expertise to add value to the organization.

### Skills

#### **Programming Language**

JavaScript
PHP
HTML/CSS
TypeScript
Shell
C/C++

#### **Frameworks**

WordPress
JQuery
Bootstrap
Ionic
React Native
Angular/Vue.JS

#### Software

Docker
Git
Nodejs/npm
Bash

#### DevOps

Linux
AWS
Google Cloud
LAMP/LEMP
cPanel/WHM

#### Language

Bangla IIIIIIII English IIIIIIIII

### Experience

# Savar Digital Polytechnic Institute. Savar, Dhaka

April 2018 - Present Junior Instructor, Department of Computer Technology.

#### Freelance Web Developer

2012 - Present

Website development and related works on various marketplace with modern web technologies and frameworks.

# Mobile & Hybrid Application Developer

2016- Present

Mobile application development using web technologies and modern tools like flutter and react native.

### Training

# IT Bangla Limited Motijheel, Dhaka.

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE)

### IT Bangla Limited

Motijheel, Dhaka. Aug 2017 - Oct 2017

Cisco Certified Network Associate

(CCNA)

### Education

# European University of Bangladesh. Gabtoli, Dhaka

Jan 2018 - Currently Enrolled B.Sc in CSE (for Diploma Holders)

# Savar Digital Polytechnic Institute. Savar, Dhaka

Aug 2013 - Dec 2017

Diploma in Computer Technology

### Radio Colony Model School

Savar, Dhaka

Passing Year - 2013

SSC in Science

### Interests

Programming Contests, Traveling, Food, Gaming, Hardware, Pets, Technology

### Personal Info

Father Name: Shahidul Haque
Mother Name: Farida Yeasmin
Date of Birth: 01 February, 1997
Permanent Pichuria, Baruria,
Address: Gopalpur, Tangail
Nationality: Bangladeshi

Religion: Islam

Marital Status: Married
Facebook arafatzahan2018

## Projects

More on: https://kuasha420.github.io/portfolio.html

# zMulti Platinum - Video Tutorial Platform

http://multi-platinum.com/

(WordPress, s2Members, WP eLearning)

A music career focused video tutorial platform. Users can purchase individual course or an all-access site membership. Course enrollment, progress tracking, progress report etc are all handled by custom integration and code.

### PageDab - Free eBook Reading PWA

http://www.pagedab.com

(lonic, epubjs, nodejs)

Ebook reading website where authors could publish their own books for free and would get paid based on hits. Serverside book rendering is done by epubjs and nodejs. The the website is a progress web app build on lonic Framework.

# The Solo Academy - Membership Website

http://www.thesoloacademy.com/

(WordPress, WP eMembers, BuddyPress)

A multi-tired membership website with activity feeds and Social networking. Built on a customized Divi theme and Elemantor.

# Backpackers News - Travel Agency Website

http://backpackersnews.co.nz

(WordPress, Woocommerce)

A travel agency website built on WordPress. It features a custom made responsive mobile friendly theme and integrates with Woocommerce for trip bookings.

### Chillao - Simple Chat App

https://github.com/kuasha420/Chillao

(React Native, Expo Framework)

A simple react native chatting application to allow shout-like chatting. Uses react native and expo framework. It also has Google Firebase Integration.

#### **TUFFLA App**

Play Store, Amazon AppStore

(Apache Cordova, Crosswalk)

TUFFLA: The ultimate fiction free library access is an all access free entertainment app that serves music, ebooks, videos and tutorials to it's users for free. It was built on Apache Cordova and later converted to Crosswalk project.

### NAMM B2B License Delivery System

https://github.com/kuasha420/namm-b2b-license-delivery (Raw PHP, MySQL, Semantic-UI)

An implementation of NAMM B2B Electronic Instant License Delivery System using php, ajax, and REST API. Built using Semantic UI. It also has backend for key management, report and other housekeeping. Keys are stored in SQL Database.

# A New And Ancient Story - Membership Website

https://newandancientstory.net/

(WordPress, s2members, BuddyPress, bbPress)

A members only community website build on WordPress using s2members, BuddyPress and various other plugins. It features an invite only flexible payment system which was custom coded for this project

I do hereby declare that all the information I have presented so far are true to my knowledge. If required & where applicable, this document can be supported by authentic certificates/papers.